MUSTAFA HAWARI

MOBILE +9779845887680

LINKEDIN Mustafa Hawari EMAIL mustafahawari64@gmail.com

STACKOVERFLOW Mustafa Hawari GITHUB @clevermustafa

UPWORK <u>Mustafa Hawari</u>

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A highly motivated and enthusiastic software developer with over 3+ years of experience in creating and deploying mobile applications. Proficient in Flutter development, with a strong understanding of the Dart programming language. Possess excellent problem-solving skills, an eye for detail, and the ability to work efficiently as part of a team or individually. Have followed MVC, MVVM, clean architecture and TDD to write code. Great knowledge of version control(git) and CI/CD pipeline.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sherpa Technologies Pvt. Ltd, Nepal (Aug 2021 to Present)

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER (FLUTTER)

- · Working on multiple projects like Dating, HR System Portal, Pet Adopt, News, etc.
- Implemented Google Maps/MapBox, Chat, In App Purchase, FCM, Authentication, Localization, Local Data Catching features and ensured their seamless integration into the overall application.
- Have used Bloc, RxDart, Provider, GetX, Riverpod for managing the application's state and ensured smooth data flow.
- · Customised Packages and Plugins as per the requirement.
- Used Figma, Adobe Xd, collaborated with the design team to implement beautiful and user-friendly UI designs.
- Debugged and resolved complex issues to maintain high application performance.
- Mentored junior developers and provided guidance on Flutter development best practices.

Larimar, Jordan - Part Time (Jun 2022 - Nov 2022)

FLUTTER DEVELOPER

- Developed UI of Wellshift, a mental health care app that processes some data and define emotional states, well-being, resilience, productivity, and abnormalities in one's vitals or states.
- Helped with localization to make the app available in 2 languages English and Arabic.
- Worked with the team to plan and prioritize the project tasks, ensuring timely delivery.
- Used Jira and Confluence for task management and documentation of the work.

Upwork, Part Time Freelancer, (Sep 2021 - Present)

MOBILE APP DEVELOPER

- Have developed, managed, designed mobile application of multiple clients.
- Helping buyer with the right technologies to grow their business.

Gauthali, Nepal, (April 2021 - July 2021)

FLUTTER INTERN

- It was product based company where I Learned the process and core concept of mobile application development, responsibilities and benefits of working in a team.
- Collaborated with the team to make E-commerce app.

Chitwan Print House (Nov 2020 - Aug 2021)

GRAPHIC DESIGNER

- Conceptualised and developed creative design solutions for brand identities, marketing collateral, web design, and print materials such as brochures, flyers, and posters.
- Used Software and tools like Adobe Photoshop, Canva to create designs.
- Communicated effectively with clients, team members, and stakeholders throughout the design process.

Part Time Tutor (2017 September - Nov 2020)

MATH TUTOR

• Mentored high school students to understand and master mathematical concepts and principles to solve their maths problem.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

THE BOOK SWAP

Common platform for buying and selling used books.

- Created mobile app with flutter where user can Register/login and list their used books to sell also can buy.
- Made web dashboard using Flutter Web where admin can view/update book list, add/update book categories and sub categories.
- · Used Firebase for backend services.
- Followed clean architecture to code for better scalability and maintainability.

HOME AUTOMATION (IOT PROJECT)

(Smart Home)

Designed and developed a home automation system.

- Worked in a team to make a system where user can control their home appliances like Bulb, Fan, Motor, etc with application.
- Contributed to the team connecting the hardware and by making application where user could check status control appliances.
- Integrated Nodemcu esp8266, ultrasonic sensor to detect the water level.
- Implemented Google Assistant to control appliances using voice command.

FULL STACK TASK APP

(Task App)

Task app to manage personal todos.

· Written well-driven code for both frontend and backend.

Wrote API code with dart using dart_frog and Flutter for frontend of the mobile app.

SKILLS

LANGUAGES FRAMEWORKS AND LIBRARIES

Dart, C, C++, Java, Kotlin, Swift Flutter, Dart frog, Injectable, Getlt, Dio.

Retrofit, Dragger-Hilt, Jetpack-Compose

DATABASES TOOLS AND TECHNOLOGIES Sqflite, PostgreSql, Cloud Firestore

Git, Codemagic, Firebase, Jira,

Confluence

EDUCATION

Bachelor of science (B. Sc.) in Computer Science and Information Technology National Infotech, Birgunj, Parsa, Nepal

+2 Science Aroma College, Bharatpur, Chitwan, Nepal

COMMUNITY EXPERIENCE

- · Local Lead Wordpress Birgunj
- Secretary National Infotech College

ACHIEVEMENTS

Local Level Winner of PROVATHON - 2021